# Jonathan Ellis

0204 065 4096 thejonathanellis@gmail.com https://jonenzl.github.io/portfolio/ www.linkedin.com/in/ellisionathan

UI, UX, and Product Designer with more than ten years experience creating engaging and effective products for large companies, SMEs, and non-profits in a wide range of fields. I am skilled at creating concepts, designing, prototyping, and developing experiences. I love working collaboratively on the whole product life cycle, from concept and strategy to design and delivery.

# Work experience

Senior User Experience Designer, Fisher & Paykel Healthcare

May 2021 - Present

User Experience Designer, Fisher & Paykel Healthcare

April 2019 - May 2021

- · Design a variety of SaaS and customer-centric products across desktop and mobile
- · Work with product owners, stakeholders, and customers to define and create solutions
- Ensure a high-level of user interface design while adhering to best practices through the creation, documentation, and delivery of design systems and guidelines
- Collaborate in a cross-functional environment with product managers, developers, testers, and marketing teams
- Create documentation including design specifications and experience/interaction specifications
- Present and communicate conceptual ideas, design guidelines and principles, and the design process within a cross-functional team
- · Plan and conduct UX research, review, and testing activities with stakeholders and customers
- Mentor and assist the growth of other members of the design team

#### **Digital Developer, Optimism**

September 2017 - March 2019

My role involves helping the team design and build learning solutions for corporates and SMEs. These projects typically include web-based learning material and quizzes, videos, animations, and interactive content.

- Translate storyboards into wireframes and mockups
- Create visual designs in line with client brand guidelines
- Develop web-based learning content, interactions, and quizzes
- Film, produce, and edit video content—including motion graphics and interactive experiences

Head of Communications, Youth With a Mission, Cambodia/Thailand

March 2012 - September 2015

My role involved leading the communications and administration teams at a large NGO in Cambodia and Thailand. I helped plan and implement improvements across the organisation.

- Designed and developed new websites for promotional, fundraising, and training purposes
- · Created books, pamphlets, postcards, and videos for fundraising campaigns
- Sat on the organisation's leadership team

#### **Designer,** Freelance

January 2010 - September 2017

My role involved providing digital, web design, and print services for a variety of clients all over the world.

- Helped clients to determine their needs, wants, and expectations for a project
- Provided expertise in how to use design to reach business goals while following best practices
- · Created designs for digital and print media, create websites using HTML and CSS

#### **Education**

# The University of Georgia

Bachelor of Environmental Science; Environmental Economics and Management 2006 - 2009

Honours: Dean's List, HOPE Scholarship Recipient

#### AMES - The Institute of IT

Diploma in Distributed Software Development 2016 - 2017

## Certifications

HavardX - CS50x: Introduction to Computer Science

Codecademy - Build Front-End Web Apps from Scratch - JavaScript, ReactJS

**Udemy** - The Web Developer Bootcamp

**NovoEd** - Design Kit: The Course for Human-Centered Design

NovoEd - Design Kit: Prototyping

### **Skills**

**Design:** User Experience Design, User Interface Design, Design Thinking, Design Sprints, concepting, sketching, wireframing, prototyping, iteration

Design Tools: Sketch, Adobe Illustrator, Adobe XD, Adobe Photoshop, Adobe InDesign

Development: Front-end development, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap, WordPress

Video Production: Adobe Premiere Pro, Adobe After Effects, Adobe Audition

Referees available upon request.